Andy Chou

andychchou@gmail.com (619) 519-9644

SUMMARY

Full stack developer with 1 year of personal experience in creating intuitive and dynamic web applications.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks, Libraries, Technologies

Redux, React, React Native, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, MongoDB

Interpersonal Skills

Team and personnel management, client collaboration, inter-departmental communication

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio - a responsive web page built using Bootstrap.

https://andychchou.github.io

Table Top Town - a table-top-themed website built using React, showcasing frontend and backend deployment.

- Home page: https://tabletoptown.herokuapp.com/
- Chess app created using JavaScript and React: https://tabletoptown.herokuapp.com/games/0/play

WORK EXPERIENCE

Novartis Gene Therapies, San Diego

Process Science Engineer

Nov 2020 - Present

Current

Supported process development as well as pipeline support.

Abzena. San Diego

4 years and 8 months Mar 2020 - Nov 2020

Senior Process Development Associate

- Managed a team of process development associates and scheduled responsibilities for staff.
- Collaborated with clients on projects, including design of experiments and project proposals.
- > Trained staff on the operation of the ambr250, a high throughput, automated 24-vessel bioreactor system.

Lead Process Development Associate

May 2019 - Mar 2020

- > Communicated with clients on a regular basis, including presentation of data and project timelines.
- > Facilitated inter-department communication to implement improvements to laboratory operations.

Process Development Associate

Jul 2017 - May 2019

Utilized Design of Experiments (DoE) and multivariate data analysis for process optimization.

Production Associate

Apr 2016 – Jul 2017

Operated stirred tank and wave bioreactors in upstream cell culture manufacturing.

AltheaDx

2 months

Lab Accessioner

Mar 2016 - Apr 2016

Received and accessioned samples into a laboratory information management system (LIMS).

EDUCATION

Nucamp

Full Stack Web and Mobile App Development

May 2021 - Nov 2021

University of California, San Diego

Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry, Department of Chemistry

2011 - 2015